# **Robert McLarty**

### hello@robmlarty.com

I have built products at startups, consulted at enterprises and SMBs, and run my own businesses. I have a background in cognitive science, artificial intelligence, philosophy, computer science, graphic design, illustration, applied research, and creative technology. I'm best suited to be in a position where I need to solve unique problems that don't fit neatly into a prescribed box (I thrive in the unknown; tailoring solutions to custom contexts). My best skill is connecting disparate ideas and concepts across problem domains that may be more difficult for specialists to notice.

At the end of the day, I like making things. I like teaching other people how to make things. And I love it when we can all make things together that are bigger than ourselves.

**Technologist** - Full-stack Software Engineering, Systems Architecture, Security & Privacy, UI/UX/IX, APIs, Infrastructure, Performance & Monitoring

Creative - Illustration, Graphic Design, Writing, Motion Graphics, Photography, Fine Art

Teacher - Visualization, Presentation, Demo, Discovery, Communication, Consulting

**Leader** - Strategy, Process, Review, Hire, Coordinate, Collaborate, Mentor, Holistic Project Management

Researcher - Imagine, Experiment, Evaluate, Connect, Exapt, Prototype, Document

# Experience

#### **Technical Director**

2023-present @ Computechnosoft

Took stagnating project from broken spaghetti code to modular, working, demo on Steam, now collecting wish-lists and marketing itself towards release candidate. Worked with artists and designers to take creative assets and integrate them with code to fulfill the interactive expression for telling the game's story and having fun.

# Principal Software Engineer

2019-2022 @ WorkTango

Helped take company from less than 10 people to 50+, being acquired by Kazoo. Focused on software & systems architecture, cloud orchestration, and security. Lead internal committees, hired new staff, organized and guided production path, and stitched everything together: systems, people, practices, and docs.

# **Staff Software Engineer**

2015-2019 @ Myplanet

Worked with Telus to develop custom proofs-of-concept for web and mobile apps requiring the highest levels of security and privacy as well as an integration of legacy and bleeding-edge tech. Also worked closely with Newstore to develop their new omnichannel retail e-commerce platform using custom serverless architecture and integrated fulfillment platform.

# Senior Developer + UI/UX Designer

2013-2015 @ Verold

Created web application platform which acted as the authz & identity system and social network for the rest of the ecosystem (3D editor, graphics engine, coding IDE) and assisted in the design and development of those parts. Spoke at conferences, consulted on strategy, and collaborated on architecture, culminating in our acquisition by Box.

### **Staff Software Engineer**

2011-2013 @ Overdrive Design

Lead technology efforts such as software development, archive process, hardware acquisition and management, staff knowledge sharing, and the hiring + onboarding of new engineers. Worked with many clients each with their own unique software challenges including custom CMSs, mobile ride hailing, museum kiosks, and custom ecommerce solutions.

#### Co-founder + CTO

2006-2011 @ Philosophy Factory

Managed office IT tasks like code versioning, asset archiving, comms, presentations and networking while also leading software development such as interface design, data modelling, code architecture, and diagnosing user experience. Coordinated contractors and kept clients updated on their projects' status. Worked with clients to design unique web presences for their brands, and provided custom software solutions such as live race results, CMSs, e-commerce, authz, games, ads, and back-office automation.

# Formal Training

### **Amazon Web Services**

2016-2018 @ AWS

Solutions Architect, Cloud Practitioner, Sysops, and Security.

# **Illustration & Graphic Design**

### 2000-2003 @ Sheridan College

Editorial, Technical, and Digital Illustration, Data Visualization, UI/UX, Motion Graphics, Web, and Print.

### **Cognitive Science**

1997-2000 @ University of Toronto Computer Science, Philosophy, Linguistics, Psychology, English, and Classics.

### **CSIA Ski Instructor**

1996-1997 @ Blue Mountain Resort & Chedoke Ski Centre Level-1 certification: entry-level skiing and basic racing.

### **Canadian Ski Patrol**

1996-1997 @ Snow Valley Resort Emergency first-aid and mountain rescue.

# **National Lifeguard**

1995-1997 @ McNab Recreation Centre
First aid and emergency response for incidents in and around pools.

# Volunteering

# **Open Source Developer + Maintainer**

1997-present @ see selected projects below

# **Director of Technology**

2023-present @ MTBCO

### **Ride Leader**

2018-2020 @ Dark Horse Cycling Club

### **Cycling Safety Advocate**

2015-2020 @ City of Toronto

### **Computer Technology Instructor**

1999-2001 @ Simcoe County Board of Education

### **Ski Patrol**

1995-1997 @ Snow Valley Resort

### **Swimming Instructor**

1995-1997 @ Hamilton Wentworth Aquatic Club

# Spoken Languages

### **English**

Native.

#### **French**

Business-Conversational.

# Computer Languages

Browser: Javascript (vanilla & ES6+), Typescript, HTML, CSS, Sass/Less

Server: Javascript (Node), Ruby, Python, Elixir, PHP, Perl

Data: SQL (Postgres/MySQL/SQLite), Redis, XML, CSV, JSON, Yaml, MongoDB

**Documentation**: Markdown, JSDoc, PEP

Infrastructure: Nginx, Apache, PM2, Docker, Bash

Network: REST, SOAP, GraphQL, Websockets, SIP, FTP, HTTP

**Game**: GDScript, Actionscript, , JS, C, C# (Unity)

General: C, C++, Ruby, Java, Python, Pascal, Turing, Basic, Lua

Templates: Haml, Nunjucks, Underscore, Liquid, ERB, EJS, Handlebars, Mustache,

JSX

# **Coding Frameworks**

**UI**: React, Angular, Preact, Backbone, jQuery, Storybook, Knockout, React Native, PhoneGap/Cordova, Electron

Server: Node, Rails, Express, Knex, Wordpress, Phoenix, Next.js, LoopBack,

CakePHP, WS, Symphony, Flask, Sinatra

Generators: 11ty, Jekyll, Hugo, Hexo, Gatsby

Styles: Normalize, Tailwind, Bootstrap, Sass/Less, MaterialUI

State: Redux, ActiveModel, Signals, PWA, Hexagonal, XState, Reactive

**Security**: NaCl, Stripe Protocol (for double-ratcheted E2EE group chat), Letsencrypt, OAuth, Cred, Auth0, Okta, OpenSSL

**Test**: Rspec, Jest, Mocha, Jasmine, Selenium, ESLint, MSW, Tape, Testunit, AVA, Enzyme, SuperTest, Chai

Game: Unity, Godot, Pixi, Phaser, FlashPunk, PushButtonEngine, Allegro

3D: Three.js, Pixi, WebGL, SketchFab, Verold

AI: PyTorch, TensorFlow.js, OpenAI

Payment: Shopify, Stripe, Authorize.net, Monaris, Lightspeed, Netsuite

Build: Rollup, ESBuild, Parcel, Webpack, Husky, Browserify, Babel, CRA, Gulp, Grunt,

Capistrano

Versioning: GIT, NPM/Yarn, NVM, RVM, SVN, n, Gem, Homebrew

Infrastructure: AWS, Digital Ocean, Media Temple, Cloudflare, Hover, Twilio, Google

Orchestration: K8s, Docker Swarm, Fargate, EC2, Passenger

Monitor: Mixpanel, Datadog, New Relic, PM2, Splunk

Deploy: Puppeteer, Github Actions, Gitlab CI, Travis CI, Bitbucket Pipelines

# **Software Tools**

**Graphics**: Photoshop, Lightroom, Illustrator, GIMP, Affinity Photo **Design**: InDesign, Quark Express, Affinity Designer, Sketch, Figma

Motion: Final Cut Pro, Premiere, Flash, After Effects Code: Sublime, Atom, Vim, Visual Studio, Notepad, CLI Communication: Discord, Slack, Teams, Zoom, Google Coordination: Trello, Notion, Jira, Assana, Basecamp

**Security**: Lastpass, 1Password, KeyPass AI: ChatGPT, Midjourney, Copilot, Flux **Versioning**: Github, Gitlab, Bitbucket **Game**: Unity, Unreal, Godot, Flash

# **Apps**

### **Safe Dose**

2023-present @ Rocket Flower

Personal medication-management tool and E2EE zero-knowledge cloud-based mobile app to securely store and share sensitive medical data with healthcare providers.

### **Hello, Cave Monster!**

2023-present @ Computechnosoft

Desktop and console tactical RPG game where the player attempts to establish friendly relations with alien beings on other worlds through communication techniques instead of fighting. Distributed on Steam.

#### **Droto**

2018-present @ Rocket Flower

Tool and method to coordinate project stakeholders more holistically, organically, and easily, with a bit of (optional) gamified fun. Secure cloud-based project management and visualization web app for individuals, SMBs, and enterprises.

### **Employee Pulse**

2019-2022 @ WorkTango

Measure and improve employee sentiment and engagement through secure anonymous surveys, business insights, and real-time dashboards. Feedback is more genuine and business-actionable when participants know their inputs are protected.

### **Wellness Messenger**

2018-2019 @ Telus

Securely coordinate the communication of sensitive and private user medical data to enable sharing only between trusted sources (e.g., doctor, technician, family).

### **Phone Collider**

2018 @ Telus

API and native app to help simplify interactions between customer endpoints and IMS systems for authz, placing & receiving calls, messaging, e911 and push notifications. Enables interaction with SIP/SMS telcom networks over IP networks.

#### **BaRSS**

2016-2017 @ Rocket Flower

Web app to read and manage multiple RSS feeds in a single easy-to-use interface that presents articles in user-configurable columns (bars) with real-time updates.

#### Verold

2013-2015 @ Verold

WebGL studio, community hub, cloud platform and API (think Unity in a web browser, plugged into its own Instagram). 3D visualization, animation, editing/modelling, codecontrolled, native web, and security.

# Co-op Ride Hail

2010-2013 @ Co-op Cabs

Standalone mobile web app and CMS integrated directly into cab company dispatch system + GPS tracking for real-time updates.

#### CAPT

2012 @ Canadian Association for Psychodynamic Therapy

Find, meet, learn, and interact with therapists nationwide, in the cloud, private and secure.

### **Burgess Shale Kiosk**

2010-2012 @ Royal Ontario Museum

Interactive exhibition kiosk touch-screen application with automated statistical analyses and backend admin controller with reporting, data management, and visualization.

### Tour d'Afrique

2006-2012 @ Tour d'Afrique Ltd

Live race tracking & results from remote locations (middle of Africa) via satellite uplink + custom CMS.

### **Sportacular Events**

2007-2008 @ Sportacular Events Inc

Regional hockey league management system. Cloud-based CMS, back-office automation, security, and events management.

# **Open Source**

#### cred

Authentication + authorization for NodeJS apps using JWT for transport. https://github.com/robmclartv/cred

#### soko

CLI tools for building and running javascript applications. <a href="https://github.com/robmclarty/soko">https://github.com/robmclarty/soko</a>

#### storium

Unified cloud storage abstraction for Knex apps. <a href="https://github.com/robmclarty/storium">https://github.com/robmclarty/storium</a>

#### fuzzle

CLI tools for static asset name reversioning. <a href="https://github.com/robmclarty/fuzzle">https://github.com/robmclarty/fuzzle</a>

# crypto-butter

Collection of cryptographic functions for web clients. <a href="https://github.com/robmclarty/crypto-butter">https://github.com/robmclarty/crypto-butter</a>

### knex api template

Example starter web server NodeJS API with scalable architecture. https://github.com/robmclarty/knex-express-project-sample

#### robchat

Double-ratcheted E2EE websocket zero knowledge (client + server) group chat app. <a href="https://github.com/robmclarty/robchat">https://github.com/robmclarty/robchat</a>

### suggestible-input

React component for fast selectable list of fuzzy-matched suggestions in an input field. https://github.com/robmclarty/suggestible-input

# paginated-redux

React/redux state management for paginated records. https://github.com/robmclarty/paginated-redux

# nginx-config

Reference nginx config files using SSL and reverse proxy. A+ rating on SSL Labs. <a href="https://github.com/robmclarty/nginx-config">https://github.com/robmclarty/nginx-config</a>

# nav\_panel

A simple navigation component for your Rails app admin interface. <a href="https://github.com/robmclarty/nav\_panel">https://github.com/robmclarty/nav\_panel</a>

# **Articles**

### What is a JSON Web Token?

https://robmclarty.com/words/articles/what\_is\_a\_jwt

### **Loop Heuristics in Javascript**

https://robmclarty.com/words/articles/loop\_heuristics\_in\_javascript

### **Docker is Fun and Easy**

https://robmclarty.com/words/articles/docker\_is\_fun\_and\_easy

### **Personal Security Tips**

https://robmclarty.com/words/articles/personal\_security\_tips

# Is There Something Better Than Time-Tracking?

https://robmclarty.com/words/articles/is\_there\_something\_other\_than\_time\_tracking

# Reduce Complexity, Not (Necessarily) Code

https://robmclarty.com/words/articles/reduce complexity not code

### **Alternative React Component Patterns**

https://robmclarty.com/words/articles/alternative\_react\_component\_patterns

# Stripe VS Paypal

https://robmclarty.com/words/articles/stripe\_vs\_paypal

# The Business of Privacy

https://robmclarty.com/words/articles/business of privacy

### **Machine Learning Is Not Learning**

https://robmclarty.com/words/articles/machine\_learning\_is\_not\_learning

# How I Learned to Stop Worrying and Love the Cascade

https://robmclarty.com/words/articles/

how i learned to stop worrying and love the cascade

### A Good Leader Aligns

https://robmclarty.com/words/articles/a good leader aligns

### Don't Use HPKP by Default

https://robmclarty.com/words/articles/dont use hpkp by default

### The Creative Process in Software Development

https://robmclarty.com/words/articles/creative process in software development

# **Installing Let's Encrypt With Certbot**

https://robmclarty.com/words/articles/installing\_letsencrypt\_with\_certbot

# Other Interests

# **Mountain Biking**

2018-present

Love my full-face DH laps (whether jumping gaps or smashing tech), but also enjoy the odd XC adventure into remote parts of the forest.

### Skiing

1995-present

Raced, patrolled, instructed, carved, and free-rided, but have still never touched a snowboard.

# Writing

1995-present

Collection of ontological investigations, technical manuals, science fiction, project management techniques, code patterns, and bad poetry.

# **Road & Gravel Cycling**

1994-present

Love getting lost in farmlands and covering vast distances with my own body's power. Climbed the highest mountain in Thailand and can pump out almost 2000W in a sprint.

### Hiking

1982-present

Adventuring off-grid with friends, around the neighbourhood with mom, or all the way to the summit of a mountain solo, nothing beats immersion in nature.

### Gaming

1980-present

Love Settlers, Chess, and Axis & Allies. Dumped many hours grinding to realm-firsts in WoW and FFXIV. My guilty pleasure is Civ V. I'm Intellivision years old.

# **Life Drawing & Painting**

1980-present

Pressed for time and direct from reality are my favourite ways to capture human beauty. Won my dad's company art contest when I was 3.

# **Swimming**

1979-present

Have been in a pool since before I could walk. Broke three Canadian age-group records which stood for over twenty years.

# References

Available upon request.